Ankit Kelkar

London, UK (Open to relocate) | Email: ankit.kelkar@gmail.com | Phone: +447438388464

Website: https://akelkar3.github.io/portfolio | LinkedIn:www.linkedin.com/in/AnkitKelkar | Github: https://github.com/akelkar3

Highlights

8+ years of experience in software development following Agile and continuous integration/ continuous delivery practices. A go to person in team to implement new and cutting-edge technologies and front end challenges. A plug and play resource.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC, USA

• Specialization in Visualization with GPA 3.9

Skills

Languages: C#, JavaScript, Java
Tools: Visual Studio, Android Studio, Eclipse, MATLAB 7.7, Unity 3D

Web Technologies: Angular, .NETCore, .NET MVC, SQL Server 2012, CSS, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, HTML5, JQuery, Entity framework, Azure Cloud

Experience

Vice President Jan 2022- Present

MIAC Analytics Itd

Web Application Development

• Managing projects in agile process and making sure the agile ceremonies are followed.

- Helped stakeholders to implement complex systems from requirements gathering and design till testing and delivery.
- Mentor incoming interns and creating a plan for their successful internship.
- Recruiting new hires and supporting the careers and professional growth of engineers.

Senior Developer Jan 2019 – Dec 2021

MIAC Analytics

Web Application Development

- Developing a financial trading application using .Net Core web api, AngularJS, Angular, SQL Server
- Implemented integration with SSRS reporting which saved more than 70% time for reporting than previous method
- Leading software teams for migration of front-end technology framework from angular IS to angular 11.
- Developed an interactive visualization tool for visualizing property rates in London boroughs
- Implemented continuous integration continuous delivery through Bamboo to ensure quality deployment.
- Advocating Azure cloud services and implementing them for required usecases.

Senior System Engineer (Software Developer)

Aug 2013 - June 2017

Graduation: Dec 2018

Infosys Limited, Pune, India

Business/Supplier Portal: Web application for Sales Team

- Developed and Maintained web application using .NET MVC4, jQuery, WCF, Entity framework and SQL Server.
- Designed UI for the application using Knockout JS and Bootstrap library.
- Developed reporting for the web application for the users.
- Performed various code optimization tasks and load testing.
- Drafted proof of concepts for various suggestion for website development to client which were highly appreciated.
- Generated Monthly and Weekly status report for team in the Agile development model.

Intern May 2018 – Dec 2018

MicroD Inc

Augmented Reality Development in 3D team

- Developing an Augmented Reality application for iOS/ Android/ HoloLens
- Rendering 3D objects through C# and web service integration
- Compared different AR Apis available for augmented reality like Vuforia, ARCore, ARKit
- Implemented MVC framework for Unity3D
- Implemented continuous integration continuous delivery through Jenkins saving deployment time

Graduate Assistant Feb 2018- Aug 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Augmented Reality Development

- Displaying demographic Data using mobile and HoloLens
- Developing a mobile application for Augmented Reality using Vuforia
- Developed 3D assets using Blender
- Exhibited the project in Urban Planning Symposium and OpenStreets704 events

Graduate Assistant Feb 2018- March 2018

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Full Stack Web application development

- Deploying a NodeJS server on a Linux system for Authentication page
- Developing an WSO2 Authentication for role-based authentication

Technical Projects

Mobile Application Development

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

- Developed full stack application using NodeJs, ExpressJS, MongoDB and MySQL with mobile app as front-end
- UI and Web application development for various apps.
- Integration of Google Maps/ Firebase Realtime Database/ Firebase Authentications APIs

Visualization of Layout of a floor for Emergency Rescue Purposes

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

Aug 2017 - Dec 2018

- Visualized a floor layout using Holo-lens
- Implemented Unity Networking for connecting two holo-lenses with server
- Visualized shortest available path to the rescue personnel through graphics aid.
- Developed Augmented Reality environment using Vuforia.

An automation system to sort threaded and unthreaded nuts using Image Processing

July 2012 - June 2013

Abhijay Group of industries

- Installed a machine vision system at the end of manufacturing line.
- Sorted the correct and incorrect parts using image processing algorithm
- Reduced human introduced counting errors and increased efficiency by 300%.
- Developed the system using Beagle-Bone hardware and OpenCV for image processing.
- Designed system's body and holder on manufacturing line using CATIA.

Achievements

• Wolfram Award in Hackathon at Duke University

- Project got Exhibited at Urban Planning Symposium and OpenStreets704 events
- Awarded Star performer in year for project work

20182013